-[insects chirping]
-[rumbling]
[dinosaurs bellowing]
[thudding]
[roars, screeches]
[Ben and Darius grunting]
Hang on!
Help! [gasping, grunting]
[Darius] Hold on, Ben!
[both gasp]
[panting]
-[screeches]
-[Ben yelps, grunts]
[grunting]
[Ben screams]
[Ben yelps]
[screeches]
[screeching]
[Brooklynn whimpers, pants]
[Kenji exhales]
[Bumpy groans]
[sighs] He's gone. He's... gone.
I won't believe it! [whimpers]
-Sammy.
-[cries] No!
[sobbing]
We're going back.
-The monorail's going back! [grunts]
-[brakes screech]
[all grunting]
What do you mean, "going back"?
When we switched tracks,
we ended up on one headed north.
We're not going to the south docks,
we're going away from them!
[grunts] Doesn't anything here work?
We gotta get off this monorail now!
[Brooklynn pants]
Oh! T-The track dips down up ahead!
We can jump there!
-[Kenji] What?
-Jump?
We can't! It's too far to jump!
It's the only way!
[exhales]
One...
-[Sammy whimpers]
-[neck cracks]
[Darius] Two...
-three!
-[Bumpy groans]
-Now!
-[all yell]
[all screaming]
-[all grunting]
-[Bumpy squeals]
[all grunting]
[Darius] Oh...
[Darius and Brooklynn grunt]
-Is everyone all right?
-[Brooklynn groans]
[grunts] "Ish." Are you?
Bumpy. Where's Bumpy?
I lost her when I hit the ground.
She's gotta be here.
-Bumpy? Bumpy!
-Shh!
There are still dinosaurs out here,
including Toro and--
Bumpy!
-Bumpy!
-We gotta look for her, don't we?
-And Ben! He might still be--
-How? We don't even know where they are!
[grunts, pants]
[male voice] Attention. All park-goers
must report to the south ferry dock
for immediate evacuation.
Last ferry departs in 60 minutes.
No chance we could get there in an hour!
It's way too far!
-Not if we leave right now!
-But Bumpy, and Ben...!
We can't go back for Ben!
Ben's...
gone.
There's just not enough time
to look for...
We can make it to the ferry,
but only if we go now.
[male voice] Last ferry departs
in 60 minutes.
[Darius sighs]
We have to go!
Repeat! Roxie and I saw you
on the monorail,
we're headed to the docks to meet you.
-[static crackles]
-Darius, do you copy?
If you can hear me,
just get to the boats, okay?
Don't stop, just keep going.
Just keep going!
[crackling continues]
They're gonna be okay, Dave.
They have to be.
[Darius pants] Keep going! Come on!
[Yasmina yelps]
Yaz!
Guys!
-Are you all--
-I'm fine.
-It's so...
-[Yasmina grunts]
-[sighs] How are you even walking?
-I'm highly motivated.
I got this.
[grunts, screams]
She can't keep up like this.
What do we do?
We can't stop, so,
we'll make a stretcher, maybe?
Or maybe there's a shortcut or...
the tunnels! Kenji!
-[grunts]
-Kenji! The maintenance tunnels.
There has to be one that leads
to the docks, right?
Kenji, right?
[hatch rattles, beeps]
[grunting]
[Kenji grunts]
This'll get us to the dock
in half the time.
[Brooklynn] Are we sure "Mr. VIP"
knows what he's doing?
Kenji took me down here before.
Just trust him.
We'll be outta here in no... time.
Everything looks different with the lights
all freaky like this, okay?
This way.
No!
[pants, sputters]
[panting]
What?
-This wasn't here before!
-Why are there so many security gates?
The evacuation. The park
must be locking down automatically!
Oh, we have to go 'round! [huffs]
This way!
[panting]
Ah!
[grunting]
[clatters]
-Oh! We can use this for--
-[grunts]
-[yelps]
-[electricity crackles]
-[crackling stops]
-A walking stick.
I'm fine!
-Unbelievable.
-Kenji!
-You said--
-[male voice] Attention.
All park-goers must report to the
south ferry dock for immediate evacuation.
Last ferry departs in 30 minutes.
-Not helping!
-Just try to remember. Breathe--
What do you think I'm doing?
Coming down here was your idea,
so just back off!
Uh, Kenji? Darius?
The way we came from...
where does that tunnel end?
It opens up into the park, I guess.
Why do you--
[snarls]
-[Kenji whimpers]
-[Brooklynn pants]
[indistinct chatter]
Okay, that's it, everybody, there we go!
Keep movin'! This way!
There were six teenagers.
You're sure you didn't see them?
What? No, I didn't notice six kids
in the middle of thousands of people here!
Right this way, sir.
Keep moving, sir, thank you.
You know, we're kind of in the
middle of an emergency evacuation!
Yeah, picked up on that.
Where's Claire Dearing?
-Who?
-Perfect!
Rox, come on.
We gotta go back and look for 'em.
No, absolutely not.
You are being evacuated.
-Are you gonna stop us?
-Yes, ma'am. I am.
That's my job.
Now, you can stay here to search,
but the last ferry departs in 25 minutes
and you need to be on it.
And if we refuse?
Then so help me, you'll be physically
placed on that boat.
And what if we refuse politely?
[snarling]
-[clatters]
-[Yasmina groaning]
[snarling]
[sighs] It's just a Compy.
-[electricity crackles]
-[squeals]
Seriously, Kenji? It's like a foot tall!
And, uh... not alone.
[snarling]
We need to go. In a group, Compies can--
Not really the time for a lesson,
dino-nerd!
Why not? It's not like you've gotten us
anywhere close to the dock, Mr. VIP!
Oh! Yeah, I'm sorry.
Don't you have some sort of
"unboxing being a brat all the time"
video to be shooting?
-[scoffs]
-Hey! Calm yourselves!
You're scaring
the itty-bitty Compy family.
"Scaring the"--? Are you for real?
After everything,
you're defending the dinosaurs?
It's not her fault you got us lost!
[scoffs] It's definitely her fault
for some of this.
Let it go, Yaz! It's just a phone!
Wait, what?
I don't even know what's going on anymore.
-Guys! Just stop--
-[roaring]
[rumbling]
[growling]
[Compies shrieking]
Toro.
-[roars]
-Here!
-[all panting]
-[footsteps thudding]
-Now you know which way to go?
-You wanna stop and ask for directions?
-[Darius] Just run!
-[snarls]
[Kenji pants, screams]
-[all scream]
-[roars]
[all panting]
[Yasmina grunting]
[roars]
-[Sammy] We can't stay here! The ferry--
-[Darius] Shh!
[Yasmina grunting]
[thud echoes]
[sighs]
-[snarls]
-[screams]
[Yasmina grunts]
[snarls]
Go, go, go!
[roars]
[whimpers, pants]
[exhales]
"Exit to south dock, one thousand feet"?
[all laughing]
[Kenji gasps]
No! No, no, no, no!
[grunts]
[both grunting]
-There's gotta be a door or...
-[Brooklynn] There's no way out.
Ugh! They must've sealed it off
after the park was finished.
Ugh! Can't anyone associated with
this place make just one good decision?
-[roar echoes]
-[all gasp]
-[all panting]
-[Darius grunting]
Darius, what do we do now?
I don't know.
-[roar in distance]
-[all gasp]
-But you always know.
-I don't know!
I don't know what to do.
I didn't know what to do about Ben,
or Bumpy,
or when the Indominus rex attacked.
-[Toro roars]
-[whimpers]
[pants, grunts]
[hyperventilates, grunts]
All I did was make bad choices
and get into trouble
and mess everything up.
[grunts]
You never should've trusted me.
I should've just stayed home.
I'm a dino-nerd who played a video game,
and I'm no good at this.
[Kenji] But you are.
Good at this.
I mean, like, I'm sure you're fine
at video games, too, not downplaying that,
but... none of us would have known
what to do, Darius.
But because you didn't give up,
we didn't give up either.
You kept us goin',
no matter what some of us have done.
You made us feel like
we were in this together.
So, we are.
We're a team. We're your team.
[Brooklynn] Things fall apart.
And that's okay
because when that happens...
We pick up the pieces and we keep going.
[grunts]
-[Toro roars]
-[Brooklynn whispers] He's getting closer.
Let's see what's in these crates.
Come on, something pointy!
Come on, something hurty!
Come on...
Ugh!
Medical supplies?
We had these around the house
after my dad got sick. [grunts]
Super compressed air,
sensitive to pressure and heat!
Might be able to scare Toro off.
Or distract him long enough
for us to find another exit.
Kenji, Brooklynn, let's get this crate
loaded on that cart.
Sammy, use those bandages
and tape to make a fuse.
We're gonna need something
to light it with.
[electricity crackling]
-[Toro roars]
-[gasps]
-[rumbling]
-[Toro snarls]
Light it up.
[electricity sputtering]
-Yaz?
-[whispers] I'm trying! It won't light!
Wait! Hand sanitizer!
This stuff will burn!
-Thanks, Ben.
-Now!
[all grunt]
[roars]
Come on, come on.
-[crashes]
-[roars]
[all yelp]
[clattering]
[all screaming]
[growls]
[roars]
Run!
-Where?
-Anywhere!
[roars]
-[Brooklynn grunts]
-[crashing]
-[snarls]
-[all screaming]
[grunting, yelling]
-[both scream]
-[snarls]
[whimpering]
[screams, grunts]
[clanging]
-[grunts]
-[snarls]
-[whimpers]
-[crashes]
[grunting]
[pants, grunts]
Thanks. [grunts]
-[grunts, yelps]
-[snarls]
[electricity crackling]
[snarls]
[grunts]
[grunts, whimpers]
-[roars]
-[grunting]
[Kenji] Darius!
-[both grunt]
-[snarls]
[hissing]
-[electricity crackling]
-[roars]
[all scream]
[roars]
[explosion]
-[electricity fizzles]
-[glass clinking]
-[all coughing]
-[Darius groaning]
-[Kenji groans]
-[coughs]
Is everyone okay?
Uh, surprisingly, yeah.
[chuckles] Whoo-hoo! We did it. We beat...
-[crumbling]
-[Kenji and Brooklynn gasp]
-[roaring]
-[all yelp]
-[panting]
-[Sammy grunts, groans]
[growls]
[snarls]
[snarls, whines]
[roars]
Yeah! That's what you get!
Take that, Toro! [grunts]
That's how you do it!
[roaring]
[Sammy laughs] Whoo-hoo!
-[Kenji] Yes!
-[cheering]
I thought we were goners!
Oh, that was scary!
Doesn't get better than that.
[Yasmina] Wanna bet?
[chuckles]
[panting]
-[seagulls cawing]
-[all panting]
[Darius] They're gone.
They're all gone.
They'll be back for us, won't they?
Of course they will.
And until then, we've got each other.
Right, Mr. VIP?
Absolutely, Dino-nerd.
Hey, don't forget "superstar."
Barf.
[Darius's voice] We thought it'd be fun.
We thought we'd be safe.
But we didn't realize the horror
waiting for us on the island.
Claws, teeth, screaming...
So much screaming.
-Despite all the hardships,
-Turn this boat around.
-we'll never give up.
-Turn it around right now!
We'll keep fighting.
That's the promise we make
every day we get.
We will survive.
We will get home.
Because no matter what happens,
no matter what this place
throws at us next,
none of us are in this alone.
[insects chirping]
[sniffs, grunts]
[Bumpy groans]
[theme music playing]